Harrison McDonald 29 year old male, Canadian Citizen

ITS Sales Engineer in Training Email: hmcdonald888@gmail.com

Cell: 416-389-7715 Home: 905-271-1648

1331 Nocutrne Court, Mississauga Ontario

# Harrison McDonald, Intelligent Transportation Sales Engineer in Training (E.I.T)

ITS Sales E.I.T Contact Information: C: 416-389-7715 T: 905-271-1648 Email: hmcdonald888@gmail.com

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Electrical Engineer in Training with over four years of experience in the Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITS) field. Strong experience configuring, deploying, installing and troubleshooting the latest ITS technology which include: Adaptive traffic control systems, non-intrusive detection systems, central traffic management systems, traffic cabinets (TS1, TS2 and TS-2 type 2 hybrid) and advanced traffic controllers. Deep understanding of the ITS industry, relevant applications for new technology and key industry players. Presently responsible for managing turn-key ITS deployments for Municipal customers across Ontario. Additional responsibilities include: Responding to RFP's, delivering technical sales presentations, preparing and following project budgets, staying abreast of the latest in ITS technology, attending industry tradeshows and building relationships with industry partners and customers. I am a trusted Professional with strong communication, management and technical skills. I am looking to leverage my industry knowledge to make transportation systems safer, more efficient and environmentally friendly.

#### **EDUCATION**

 Bachelor of Electrical Engineering Carleton University (2010 – 2015)

### SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE

- AutoCad
- MS office product suit
- Synchro signal timing analysis
- Centracs 2.0
- JD Edwards

## PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

- Professional Engineers Ontario (PEO) EIT program, P.Eng Eligible
   June 01/2019 application in progress
- WHMIS
- IMSA Public Safety Technician
- IMSA Traffic Signal Technician Level I

### **EXPERIENCE**

Black & McDonald Limited (September 2018 – Present) Address: 31 Pullman Court Toronto Ontario ITS Sales Engineer in Training (E.I.T.)

Econolite Canada (May 2015 – September 2018) Address: 110 Travail Rd. Markham Ontario Intelligent Transportation Systems E.I.T.

#### **Future Security Control (2014)**

Junior Controller – Part Time Security Control Center Technician

# L3 Communications (2012 - 2013)

Co-op Engineering Student – Electrical Engineering Dept.

# L3 Communications (Summer Inter June – August, 2010 – 2011)

Summer Intern – Systems Engineering Dept.

### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Black & McDonald Limited (September 2018 – Present): ITS Sales E.I.T.

• Responsible for configuring, selling and marketing Black & McDonald Limited ITS product lines. Preparing project

Harrison McDonald • 2019 (Page 1 of 2)

Harrison McDonald 29 year old male, Canadian Citizen

ITS Sales Engineer in Training Email: hmcdonald888@gmail.com

Cell: 416-389-7715 Home: 905-271-1648

1331 Nocutrne Court, Mississauga Ontario

budgets, schedules, coordinating with sub-contractors and project stake holders. Delivering presentations, information webinars, and product demonstrations. Forging and maintaining productive relationships.

- Customers include Municipalities across Ontario and the Ministry of Transportation. Serving as the Prime Contractor, services include: Supplying request technology, estimating project budget, mobilizing and supervising man-power, preparing traffic control and project safety plans.
- Ensuring clear communication with upper management, and project stakeholders. Preparing and presenting bi-weekly business reports.

## Econolite Canada (May 2015 – September 2018): ITS Technical Support E.I.T.

Gained valuable industry experience working as a technical support E.I.T. Duties included: Traffic controller programming, traffic cabinet design, detection system installation and configuration, ATMS configuration and troubleshooting (Centracs), logic script programming (using the ASC3 logic processor), field installation support and remote technical support for all Econolite products. Worked closely with Municipal technologists/engineers to deploy, support and trouble-shoot all Econolite ITS solutions.

# Experience in configuring and deploying the following ITS systems (and many more):

- Autoscope Encore & Vision camera detection systems: Extensive experience in the installation and configuration requirements of the Autoscope video based detection system. Developed detailed testing documentation for these product lines such that no systems are shipped without being carefully tested.
- In-ground Puck/Pod detection systems: Developed detailed testing procedures for Puck/Pod in-ground detection systems. Field experience deploying and configuring these solutions. Duties included radio configuration, puck identification, repeater configuration and access point configuration.
- Smartmicro Radar detection system: Full understanding of the requirements for this system, ideal applications and the installation/configuration process. Led field installations and has an excellent relationship with the Smartmicro product team
- Advanced Traffic Controllers: In-depth experience programming and debugging traffic controllers for both standard and
  non-standard intersection applications. Experience with all aspects of controller programming from Time of Day
  coordinated patterns to logic processor scripts designed for customer specific applications. Understanding of the
  limitations of the standard traffic controllers and how to work within them to produce the results required of customers.
- Traffic Cabinets (TS 1 and TS 2): Successfully tested, debugged and designed NEMA TS1 and TS2 traffic cabinets for numerous Municipalities across Canada. Experience in configuring traffic cabinets to run 8 phase quad configuration, 4 phase configuration and non-standard custom configurations. Understanding of all associated hardware required for functional traffic cabinets. (Detector rack, SDLC bus, power supply, MMU/CMU etc.)
- **Centracs ATMS:** Worked with several Municipalities to install Centracs servers, migrate traffic signals to the Centracs system, setup communication channels, trouble shoot system errors and train city staff. Harrison's clients included: The Region of York, Region of Niagara, City of Brantford and Region of Waterloo.
- Transit Signal Priority/EVP: Experienced in programming TSP, Rail and EVP plans in traffic controllers and installing the required in-cabinet/on-street hardware and interfacing with Centeral Systems.
- Adaptive Traffic Control Systems: Understands the configuration requirements of both centralized and de-centralized adaptive traffic control systems, the pros and cons of each systems, costs associated with deployments and detection requirements.
- Audible Pedestrain button programming and installation
- Traffic Cabinet Uninterruptible power supply system programming and installation
- Traffic Counting and Classification Sensor (portable and fixed) programming and installation